Guide to the Thomas Merton Center Records, 1962-2009 AIS.1982.19
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Fifth Deposit (2009), 1962-2009; V.
  - Audio/Visual, 1967-1997; 3.
    - Audio
      - Sheila Collins, Chains that Bind, Second Conference on the Ordination of Roman Catholic Women, 1978 (Box 61, Cassette 89)
      - Frances Moore Lappe, World Hunger, 1975 (Box 61, Cassette 90)
      - Reverend John McRaith, "Food and Agriculture: Who Eats?", 1979 (Box 61, Cassette 91)
      - Sharing Global Resources, 1977 (Box 61, Cassette 92)
      - Why Hunger? (Box 61, Cassette 93)
      - Andrew Young, "Racism and the War", Al Hubbard Vietnam Veterans Against the War, Pat Reardon "Abraham and Faith", "Death", 1972 (Box 62, Reel 1)
      - Animals (Box 62, Reel 2)
      - Father Donald McIlvane, Thomas Merton Center New Person Award Dinner, June 7, 1973 (Box 62, Reel 3)
      - Gods of Metal, ca. 1983 (Box 62, Reel 4)
      - James Carroll, "Reflections on Being Mild" Part I, Homily at Mass, "Contemplation", 1972 (Box 62, Reel 5)
      - James Carroll, "Reflections on Being Mild" Part III, "Prayer" (Box 62, Reel 6)
      - James Carroll, "Resistance and Contemplation", Poetry (Box 62, Reel 7)
      - Joe Hughes and Larry Kessler (TMC founder), WDUQ, December 1973 (Box 62, Reel 8)
      - Molly Rush and Joe Hughes, WTAE Radio Ron Jaye Talk Show, Neutron Bomb and Arms Race, Part I & II, September 11, 1977 (Box 63, Reel 9-10)
      - Nonviolence: Tivoli, Dorothy Day, et all, 1967, 1969 (Box 63, Reel 11)
      - Pat Reardon, "Vocation and Conversion", Joe Reardon, "Thomas Merton Prophet" (Box 63, Reel 12)
      - Seymour Melman, "Economic Conversion", E.C. Bloke, "International Response to War", Dean Stendal, "Judgement and Mercy" (Box 63, Reel 13)
      - Time (Box 63, Reel 14)
      - Brazilian Bishops, "I Have Heard the Cry of My People" (Box 64, Reel 15)
      - James Carroll, "Building Community via Liturgy and Social Apostulate", "Community" (Box 64, Reel 16)
      - James Carroll, "Liturgy", "Poverty, Charity, Obedience and Contemplative Activism in Social Apostulate" (Box 64, Reel 17)
      - Father Joseph Healy, "Come to Life", "Connections", "Immediacy" (Box 64, Reel 18)
      - Father Joseph Healy, "The Converted Church", Dave Cormier, "United Farm Workers" (Box 64, Reel 19)
      - Father Joseph Healy, "Humor", Father Tazoli, "Collapse" (Box 64, Reel 20)
      - White Against Black (Box 64, Reel 21-23)
    - Video
      - Andrew Carnegie, American Experience, PBS, 1997 (Box 65, Video 1)
      - Building Pittsburgh, 1991 (Box 65, Video 2)
      - Chain of Life, Women and Civil Disobedience, River City Campaign (Box 65, Video 3)
      - Children at Risk (Box 65, Video 4)
      - Life Together: The Hutterian Bruderhof (Box 65, Video 5)
      - Oxfam America Community, Bangladesh (Box 65, Video 6)
      - Put-Down, Franciscan Communications Center, 1973 (Box 65, Video 7)